Guide to the Rice University Parking Committee records, 1996-2001 UA 235
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Parking Committee records
1996-2001
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University.
UA 235
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The collection consists of records of the work of the presidentially appointed committee of faculty, staff, and students responsible for planning parking arrangements and policies for the Rice campus. Among the subjects discussed were fees for parking in varied locations, costs of the bus system, and the installation of a traffic light at the Rice Boulevard campus boundary.
Biographical / Historical
The Parking Committee is one of fifteen standing committees appointed by the president. At its largest, it numbered nineteen people, a combination of faculty, staff, and students. In 1996-97 and 1997-98 the chairman was Wil Uecker. William Cannady, who had been on the committee in the preceding years, became chairman in 1998-99 and served in that role for the remaining years represented in the collection.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of records of the work of the Rice University committee of faculty, staff, and students appointed by the president to assess needs, plan provision of space, and establish policies related to parking on the campus. Developments that occurred during the years represented in these records include establishment of fees for parking, and relating revenue to the cost of the campus bus service. Also included is documentation of the planning and negotiation with the City of Houston in order for a traffic light to be installed at the Rice Boulevard boundary of the campus where it meets Sunset Boulevard.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to Fondren Library circa 2001.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Transportation
Document Types
documents
- Series I: Parking diagrams
  - Campus and Area Diagrams (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Meeting contents and correspondence
  - 1996-1997 Meeting Content and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1997-1998 Meeting Content and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1998-1999 Meeting Content and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1999-2000 Meeting Content and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 2000-2001 Meeting Content and Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 2001 Committee Membership and Sept. 19 Meeting (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series III: Parking Study report and diagram, oversize
  - Rice University Parking Study report, directed by O. Jack Mitchell, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Rice Unviersity Campus Parking Lots, 1962 (Box 2)